A Finding Aid to the Andrew Carnduff Ritchie Papers, 1907-1983, in the Archives of American Art AAA.ritcandr2
Archives of American Art
Andrew Carnduff Ritchie papers
1907-1983
AAA.ritcandr2
Archives of American Art
10.3 Linear feet
The papers of museum director, professor, writer, and post-World War II Monuments Men Andrew Carnduff Ritchie measure 10.3 linear feet and date from 1907 to 1983. Found within the papers are biographical material, including materials and photographs concerning his military service in the Monuments, Fine Arts, and Archives Section of the U.S. Army; correspondence, including letters from numerous artists; writings; committee and organization files; exhibition and project files, teaching files; printed material; and photographs, including portrait images of Ritchie taken by Hans Namuth.
Ritchie, Andrew Carnduff
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged as 8 series.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1907-1978 (0.5 linear feet; Box 1, OV 11)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1928-1983 (2.2 linear feet; Boxes 1-3)
Series 3: Writings, 1927-1978 (2.9 linear feet; Boxes 3-6, OV 11)
Series 4: Committee and Organization Files, 1948-1971 (1.2 linear feet; Boxes 6-7)
Series 5: Exhibition and Project Files, 1949-1978 (1.6 linear feet; Boxes 7-9, OV 12)
Series 6: Teaching Files, 1957-1974 (0.5 linear feet; Box 9)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1928-1978 (0.5 linear feet; Boxes 9-10)
Series 8: Photographs, 1935-1982 (O.9 linear feet; Box 10, OV 13)
Biographical/Historical note
Andrew Carnduff Ritchie (1907-1978) was a museum director, professor, and art historian based in New York and Connecticut. He served as director of the Albright Knox Gallery in Buffalo, N.Y., director of Painting and Sculpture at the Museum of Modern Art, and director of the Yale University Art Gallery.
Andrew Carnduff Ritchie was born in Bellshill, Scotland, in 1907 to Andrew and Jeanie Gilchrist Ritchie. The family immigrated to the United States when he was 15 and settled in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. He attended the University of Pittsburgh and received a bachelor's and master of arts degrees in medieval art, and his doctoral degree from the University of London in 1935. That same year, he married Jane Thompson.
From 1935 to 1942, Ritchie was a researcher and lecturer at the Frick Collection in New York City and faculty member at New York University, as well as a visiting lecturer at Johns Hopkins University in Baltimore, Maryland.
In 1942, Ritchie was appointed director of the Albright Knox Gallery in Buffalo, New York where he stayed until 1949 when he became the director of Painting and Sculpture at the Museum of Modern Art.
In 1945-1946, directly following World War II, Ritchie served with the U.S. Army's Monuments, Fine Arts, and Archives section in Austria and helped with the restitution of art looted by the Nazis, returning paintings and cultural artifacts back to their country of origin. He was later honored by France and the Netherlands for this work.
In 1957, Ritchie accepted the postion of director of the Yale University Art Gallery where he stayed until 1971. While there, he acquired notable works of art for the Gallery's collections by David Smith, Noguchi, and Maillol. Thanks to Ritchie's efforts and guidance, art collector and patron Paul Mellon donated his collection of British art and established the Yale Center for British Studies. In 1971, Ritchie also became the Clark Professor at Williams College, Massachusetts, and, in 1972, he was a visiting professor at the University of Sydney, Australia. Ritchie retired from Yale in 1973.
Ritchie was also awarded honorary doctorates from the University of Pittsburgh and the Royal College of Art in London. He wrote several books over the course of his career and passed away in Canaan, Connecticut, in 1978.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. research facility.
Existence and Location of Copies note
Five letters from Alfred H. Barr to Ritchie are available on 35 mm microfilm reel 2786, frames 1109-1123 at the Archives of American Art offices, and through interlibrary loan.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
This collection was donated in multiple installments in 1979 and 1981 by Andrew Ritchie's widow, Jane T. Ritchie, and by her estate in 1986. Five letters from Alfred Hamilton Barr to Andrew and Jane Ritchie were donated in 1974 by Andrew Ritchie through Russell Lynes.
Related Archival Materials note
Among the holding at the Archives of American Art is an interview of Andrew Carnduff Ritchie conducted in 1977 June 16-17 by Paul Cummings.
The Albright-Knox Gallery Archives in Buffalo, New York has a collection of Andrew Carnduff Ritchie papers, which include administrative records and correspondence.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of museum director, professor, writer, and post-World War II Monuments Men Andrew Carnduff Ritchie measure 10.3 linear feet and date from 1907 to 1983. Found within the papers are biographical material, including materials and photographs concerning his military service in the Monuments, Fine Arts, and Archives Section of the U.S. Army; correspondence, including letters from numerous artists; writings; committee and organization files; exhibition and project files, teaching files; printed material; and photographs, including portrait images of Ritchie taken by Hans Namuth.
Biographical materials include birth certificates, passports, academic records, biographical profiles, and awards. There are files documenting Andrew Carnduff Ritchie's post-World War II military service in 1945-1946 as a "Monuments Men" in the Monuments, Fine Arts, and Archives (MFAA) section of the U.S. Army, including correspondence, forms, reports, photographs (including 7 of paintings looted from Holland), and awards. There is also a file on the Fogg conference on the emergency protection of artwork dated 1939-1942 and one file regarding the Frick Collection's orders for protecting art. There is also a folder of material on his wife Jane Ritchie.
Alphabetical and chronological correspondence is with artists, museums, galleries, universities, and colleagues. The bulk of the alphabetical correspondence consists of letters from artists such as Afro, Alexander Calder, Dimitri Hadzi, Russell Lynes, Eduardo Paolozzi, Theodore Roszak, and others. There are also condolence letters addressed to Jane Ritchie. Chronological correspondence includes Ritchie's correspondence on the subject of travels, lectures, projects, and exhibitions.
Writings include one disbound notebook, papers from college and graduate studies, lecture drafts, outlines, and notes. There are a few writings by others.
Committee and organization files document Ritchie's work on advisory panels, trustee boards, councils, board of directors, and committees. There are meeting minutes, bulletins, reports, studies, and correspondence. Some of the more voluminous files include the College Art Association's study on "The Visual Arts in Higher Education" as well as the Museum of Modern Art's committee on museum collections.
Exhibition and project files include correspondence, printed material, photographs, catalogs, and assorted documents. Among the projects and exhibitions in this series are Ritchie's work on the Alfred E. Burr Memorial in Connecticut and the Middelheim Sculpture exhibition.
Teaching files contain correspondence, program outlines, course materials, recommendations, and a few student papers from universities and programs where Ritchie taught, including Yale University Art Gallery.
Printed material consists of news clippings, some of which are arranged by subject, along with articles by Andrew Ritchie, press releases, magazines, bulletins, and a few exhibition catalogs.
Photographs are of Andrew Ritchie, and of friends and artists at various art openings and events. There is one small album of photographs of a birthday party for Jane Ritchie. Also included are photographs of artwork.
Afro, 1912-1976; Allied Forces. Supreme Headquarters. Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives Section.; Calder, Alexander, 1898-1976; College Art Association of America.; Hadzi, Dimitri, 1921-2006; Lynes, Russell, 1910-1991; Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.).; Namuth, Hans; Paolozzi, Eduardo, 1924-2005; Ritchie, Jane; Roszak, Theodore, 1907-; Yale University. Art Gallery.; Art thefts--Germany--History--20th century; Art treasures in war--Netherlands--History--20th century; Art--Study and teaching; Arts administrators--Connecticut--Canaan; Authors--New York (State)--New York; Cultural property--Protection--Europe--History--20th century; Educators--Connecticut--Canaan; Museum directors--New York (State)--New York; Photographs; World War, 1939-1945--Art and the war; World War, 1939-1945--Confiscations and contributions--Germany; World War, 1939-1945--Destruction and pillage--Europe
- Biographical Material, 1907-1978; Series 1; 0.5 Linear feet Box 1, OV 11
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical materials include birth certificates, passports, academic records, biographical profiles, awards, resumes, obituaries, and honorary degrees. There are files documenting Andrew Ritchie's military service after World War II as part of the Monuments, Fine Arts, and Archives (MFAA) section of the U.S. Army, and two files concerning the protection of artwork in the U.S. Found within the MFAA files are correspondence, army forms and reports, photographs of paintings looted from Holland, and awards. There is also a folder of biographical material on his wife, Jane Ritchie.
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged chronologically. The MFAA material is grouped separately after the other biographical folders.
  - Certificates, 1907-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Army Forms and Certificates, 1935-1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Academic Record of Andrew C. Ritchie", circa 1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Drawings and Sketches by Unidentified Artist, circa 1945-circa 1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Passport, 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Biographical Profiles, circa 1956-1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Federal Aviation Agency Plaque for Distinguished Service, circa 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Royal College of Arts Honorary Doctorate, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Oversized material housed in OV 11.
  - Obituaries, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Jane Ritchie Biographical Material, 1930-1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Monuments, Fine Arts, and Archives Section (Box 1)
    - Fogg Conference on Emergency Protection of Artwork, 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Frick Collection Orders for Protecting Art, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence and Clippings about Bomb Damage and Looting in Italy, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Inventory of Austrian Art at Munich Central Collecting Point, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Memorandums and Documents on "Recovery of Art After WWII", 1946 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Reports and Lectures of Art Restitution, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Photographs of Habsburg Jewels of the Holy Roman Empire at Munich, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Photographs of MFAA Soldiers Recovery of Madonna and Child, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Photographs of Art Recovery and Collecting Points, circa 1945 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Includes 1 photograph of the Ghent Altarpiece on display at unidentified location, probably a museum.
    - Order of Orange-Nassau from Netherlands, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - French Legion of Honor, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - German Order of Merit, 1957-1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Oversized Honorary Doctorate from Box 1, Folder 8, 1970 (Box OV 11)
- Correspondence, 1928-1983; Series 2; 2.2 Linear feet Boxes 1-3
  Alphabetical and chronological correspondence is with artists, friends, museums, galleries, universities, and colleagues in the art world. The alphabetical correspondence includes many letters from artists, including Afro, Alexander Calder, Herbert Ferber, Dimitri Hadzi, Russell Lynes, Jean Helion, Eduardo Paolozzi, Theodore Roszak, Franklin Watkins, and others. There are also condolence letters addressed to Andrew Ritchie's widow, Jane Ritchie. Chronological correspondence is with museums, universities, friends, artists, and colleagues on the subject of travels, lectures, projects, and exhibitions.
  - Afro, circa 1951-1964 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Barr, Alfred Hamilton, 1944-1958 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Barr, Margaret "Marga" Scolari, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - B, Miscellaneous, 1949-1983 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Calder, Alexander, 1951-1974 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - C-D, Miscellaneous, 1947-1956 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Ferber, Herbert, 1969-1975 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - G, Miscellaneous, 1953-1958 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Hadzi, Dimitri, 1957-1970 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Helion, Jean, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - H-J, Miscellaneous, 1947-1980 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - J. J. Little & Ives Co., Inc., 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Lebrun, Rico, circa 1964 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Lynes, Russell, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - L, Miscellaneous, 1945-1973 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Meadows, Bernard, 1954-1982 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Moore, Henry, 1954-1972 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - M-N, Miscellaneous, 1937-1961 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Paolozzi, Eduardo, circa 1959 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Price, Vincent, circa 1970 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Ritchie, Jane, 1928-1983 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Roszak, Theodore, 1958-1977 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Royal Society of Arts, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - R, Miscellaneous, 1951-1972 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Smith, David, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - S-V, Miscellaneous, 1950-1957 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Watkins, Franklin, 1959-1965 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Weinberg, Elbert, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Williams College, 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Yale University, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Yale University Appointment Congratulations Letters, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Condolence Letters, A-D, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Condolence Letters, F-L, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Condolence Letters, L-Z, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Condolence Letters, A-K, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Condolence Letters, M-S, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Condolence Letters, T-W, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Condolence Letters from Correspondents without Surnames, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1935-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1-33)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1965-1978 (Box 3, Folder 1-17)
  - Holiday Greeting Cards, 1939-1956 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Writings, 1927-1978; Series 3; 2.9 Linear feet Boxes 3-6, OV 11
  Writings include undergraduate and graduate papers and theses from University of Pittsburgh and University of London, lecture drafts, outlines, notes, one disbound notebook from Andrew Ritchie's time working at the Frick Collection, and some writings by others.
  Prior to their arrival at the archives, the papers underwent some preliminary arrangement. Insofar as it was possible, the folders dedicated to a specific lecture or paper were labeled by title, then arranged chronologically. Other folders generically labeled "lecture drafts and notes" and "lectures" contained a mixture of drafts and notes on multiple lectures. These folders retained their original titles and were grouped separately, then arranged in loose chronological order. Some of the folders have overlapping dates due to the assortment of lectures and material within.
  - Disbound Notebook, circa 1937 (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
  - University of Pittsburgh (Box 3)
    - School Papers, 1927-1933 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Sociology Paper, circa 1930 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - School Paper, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Graduate School Papers and Notes, circa 1932-circa 1933 (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
  - Note Cards for Thesis, circa 1933 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - University of London (Box 4)
    - Doctoral Notes, circa 1935 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Doctoral Notes and Drafts, circa 1935 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
    - "Peterborough Choir Stall Paintings" List for Thesis, circa 1935 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
  - New York University Course and Lecture Outlines, 1935-1941 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - English Painting Seminar Lecture Outlines, circa 1937-1941 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - English Painting Seminar Lecture Outlines, circa 1938 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - English Painting Seminar Lecture Notes, circa 1938 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Victorian Art Lectures, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Frick Symposium Lecture and Papers, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - "Hogarth as a Painter", 1946 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - "20th Century American Sculpture", 1958 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - "Ten American Sculptors" Exhibition Catalog Drafts, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - "Ten American Sculptors" Exhibition Catalog Photographs of Art, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Franklin Watkins Lecture and Printed Material, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - "Some Aspects of 20th Century Sculpture," Amhert College, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - "Henry Moore Inaugural Lecture Series," Art Gallery of Ontario, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Lecture Drafts and Notes, 1933-1938 (Box 4, Folder 19-25)
  - Lecture Drafts and Notes, 1936-1957 (Box 5, Folder 1-25)
  - Lectures, 1942-1975 (Box 6, Folder 1-8)
  - Slide Lists for Lectures, 1966-1971 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Writings by Others (Box 6)
    - "Preliminary Memorandum on Morale of Government Departments", 1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Thesis by Margaret Ames, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Royal College of Art Convocation Speech, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - "Retirement Haiku" by John, circa 1971 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Russell Lynes Writing About Andrew and Jane Ritchie, circa 1978 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Oversized School Paper from Box 3, Folder 23, circa 1933 (Box OV 11)
- Committee and Organization Files, 1948-1971; Series 4; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 6-7
  Andrew Ritchie served on many advisory panels, trustee boards, councils, board of directors, and committees during his career, and the materials related to those activities are included in this series. There are meeting minutes, bulletins, reports, and studies, though the bulk of the material is correspondence. Some of the more voluminous and noteworthy committees and organizations include the College Art Association's study on "The Visual Arts in Higher Education" as well as the Museum of Modern Art's committee on museum collections. There are also a few folders on club memberships.
  This series is organized alphabetically by the name of the organization or committee.
  - American Federation of the Arts, 1963-1967 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Archives of American Art, New York Committee, 1958-1966 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Artists Equity Association, 1949-1956 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Association of Art Museum Directors, 1952-1970 (Box 6, Folder 18-20)
  - Brandeis University Board of Overseers, 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Brandeis University Sculpture Award Jury, 1968-1970 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Buffalo Fine Arts Academy Meeting Minutes, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - College Art Association (Box 6)
    - Museum Training Conference, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Advisory Committee, 1960-1969 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Report, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - "Visual Arts in Higher Education" Study, Ford Foundation Grant, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - "Visual Arts in Higher Education," Pre-Study Meeting Summaries, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - "Visual Arts in Higher Education," Research File, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - "Visual Arts in Higher Education," Copy of Report, circa 1963 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - "Visual Arts in Higher Education," Charts and Tables, circa 1963 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - "Visual Arts in Higher Education," Correspondence, 1964-1971 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - College Art Association, "Visual Arts in Higher Education" Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Commission on the Humanities Sub-Committee, 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Commission on the Humanities Report, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Government and Art, 1950-1957 (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
  - Connecticut Commission on the Arts, 1966-1970 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Federal Aviation Agency Art Advisory Panel, 1961-1965 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - First National City Bank Art Collection Review Panel, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Limestone Trout Club, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Lincoln Center Art Committee, 1960-1966 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art Committee for Centennial Celebration, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Minneapolis Institute of Arts, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Minneapolis Institute of Arts Photographs of Art, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Museum of Modern Art Committee on Museum Collections, 1951-1957 (Box 7, Folder 14-16)
  - National Council of Churches Commission on Art, 1957-1959 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - National Council on the Arts and Government, 1960-1969 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Princeton University Art Museum Advisory Council, 1968-1971 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Rhode Island School of Design Fine Arts Committee, 1964-1969 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - University of Notre Dame Art Gallery Advisory Council, 1968-1971 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Virgina Museum of Fine Arts Selection Committee, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Yale University Art Gallery, 1957-1971 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - "Yale, Your Neighbor" Radio Program Transcript, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Yale Conference on British Art, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Yale Center for British Art, 1966-1977 (Box 7, Folder 26-27)
  - Yale Center for British Art, Arrangement of the Mellon Collection, circa 1967 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Yale Club of New York, 1963-1970 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Exhibition and Project Files, 1949-1978; Series 5; 1.6 Linear feet Boxes 7-9, OV 12
  This series includes correspondence, printed material, photographs, catalogs, and assorted documents related to art projects and numerous exhibitions for which Andrew Ritchie curated, planned, wrote, or judged. Some of the projects and exhibitions in this series include the Alfred E. Burr Memorial in Connecticutt, the Middelheim Sculpture exhibition in 1971, and the Western Round Table on Modern Art in 1949.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by project title.
  - Aid to Special Exhibitions Program, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Alfred E. Burr Memorial, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 31-32)
    Oversized material housed in OV 12.
  - Alfred E. Burr Memorial Photographs of Fountain, circa 1972 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Bill to Establish a National Registry of Art, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Carnegie Program on American Art, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Centurions Sculpture Show, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Ford Foundation Arts Consultant, 1971-1973 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Ford Foundation Catalogs Program, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "German Art of the 20th Century" (1957), 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
  - Middelheim Sculpture Exhibition (1971), 1970-1971 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence and Planning, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Financial Material, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - "Installation and Assembly Manual" and Photographs of Art, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
  - Niagara Frontier Convocation, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
  - O'Hare Field Mural Project, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Oscar B. Cintas Estate Collection, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Oscar B. Cintas Estate Collection Photographs, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Portland Art Museum Sculpture Purchase Program, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Portland Art Museum Sculpture Purchase Program Photographs of Art, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Protecting Museum Collections from Bombing, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Sainsbury Centre for Visual Arts, Correspondence with University of East Anglia, 1975-1978 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Sainsbury Centre for Visual Arts Opening, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Sao Paulo Bienal Jury, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Seattle Bank Building Art Consultant, 1968-1971 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Southern Illinois University Seminar, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 21)